Brendan Luchen

brendan@luchenlabs.com github.com/Cheezmeister

Synopsis

Eclectic and motivated frontend engineer with fullstack and devops capability.

A decade in the field and the optimistic cynicism to prove it.

An informed holistic view of software's purpose as an effective solution to a real problem.

Employed as an engineer; self-identify as a maker.

SKILLS

	Proficient	Competent	Familiar
Programming	EcmaScript family	C, C#, C++	Perl, Haskell
	Ruby	Scala, Python, CSS	Elixir, Elm
Markup/Data	Markdown, JSON, Pug	Haml, HTML	Yaml, Stylus, Sass
Libraries/API	SDL, NodeJS, React	Rails, OpenGL	Phoenix, Ionic/Angular
Tools/Software	git, Vim, tmux	Docker, Heroku	GIMP, GDB, Ansible
Spoken Language		Spanish	Japanese, German

(Not an exhaustive list)

EDUCATION Rochester Institute of Technology

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science

Dual Minors, German Language and Mathematics

• Magna cum laude

• Study abroad in Dubrovnik, Croatia

SHIPPED

Chromathud: Educational puzzle game for PC and Xbox Live Indie Games

SOFTWARE OverClocked Jukebox: Web jukebox for videogame arrangements from ocremix.org

Modern Warfare 3: Multiplatform first-person shooter (© Activision)

Haiku for Android: Thin client to Epic's electronic medical record (© Epic)

Teikametrics Flywheel: The eCommerce Seller's Operating System (© Teikametrics)

EMPLOYMENT Teikametrics

Boston, Massachusetts

Rochester, New York

May 2011

Software Engineer II (SE2)

Feb 2019-present

Flywheel is an eCommerce seller toolkit, offering ad-spend optimization, inventory management, market intelligence, and premium managed services with in-house analysts.

- Delivered an automated billing backend, enabling some \$25k of MRR to be automatically invoiced and charged, a previously manual process.
- Developed internal tooling to automate routine dev tasks, viz. migration from Flywheel 1 to 2.0
- Presented "Lunch and Learns" on topics including: History of Frontend; Phoenix on Elixir; Brendan's Peculiar Workstation.

Technologies: SQL (Postgres), Docker, Heroku, Ruby, Rails, React, Typescript, Scala, Cats, Tailwind-CSS, Python, Bash, Go, Datadog, Terraform, Kubernetes

Past Applied Training Systems, Inc.

Software Engineer

Employment

Seattle, Washington

April 2017–August 2018

Reviewsnap and Trakstar are mature and well-tuned performance management systems.

- Pioneered a docker-based development environment to speed up onboarding
- Reviewed team members' work to ensure a high quality bar

Technologies: Python, Swagger, Docker, Ruby, Rails, React, Sass

Comcast Technology Solutions

Seattle, Washington

Software Development Engineer in Test (SDET)

August 2014-November 2016

Comcast Technology Solutions (nee "the Platform") designs custom solutions for digital media companies to manage and publish video and audio.

- Owned E2E testing of commissioned work in "productively adversarial" relation to development
- Verified code allowing Comcast subscribers on Apple TV to login with their Apple ID
- Built an improved CLI and GUI to access the firm's proprietary data backend

Technologies

Java, Spring, Node/AngularJS, TestNG, OpenStack, AWS, Chef, Gatling, Upsource, REST, Literate CoffeeScript, Jenkins, TeamCity

Amazon Seattle, Washington

Software Development Engineer (SDE)

June 2013–February 2014

- Drove company-wide initiatives to reduce HTTP 5xx and other failures (FATALs)
- \bullet Shared 24/7 pager-duty rotation with a team of 2–4 developers

Technologies

Epic

JavaScript, jQuery, Spring, Java, Hibernate, Ruby, Rails, InnoDB, Brazil/Apollo

Software Developer

September 2011–March 2013

Madison, Wisconsin

• Prototyped and developed Haiku for Android, Epic's mobile sidekick for physicians

Technologies

Java, Android, ADK, M (MUMPS), C/.NET, VB6, Chronicles